Hello, and welcome to Lesson 15 of this introduction to calculus with Wolfram U.
大家好，欢迎来到本次与沃尔夫兰大学合作的微积分入门第15课。
The topic for this lesson is linear approximations.
本节课的课题是线性近似。
Let’s begin with a brief overview of this lesson. You may recall that the derivative of a function
我们先来简单介绍一下本节课的内容。你可能还记得函数的导数
is calculated by zooming in on it with some limits. Typically you take some limit as,
是通过放大它的一些限制来计算的。通常情况下，你取一些限制为：
let’s say, h→0 or some other variable, and the point is that as you get closer and closer
比方说，h →0或其他变量，而问题是，当你越来越靠近
to a desired point, then the function begins to look like its tangent line.
到所需的点，那么函数就开始看起来像它的切线。
For example, here’s a function f[x] = x^2, and that’s the function, that’s the tangent line.
例如，这里有一个函数f[x]=x^2，这就是函数，这就是切线。
We can see that very close to the point (1, 1), they both look essentially identical.
我们可以看到，在非常接近点（1，1）的地方，它们都看起来基本相同。
You can use this property to approximate a function near a point with its tangent line,
你可以使用这个属性用它的切线来逼近一个点附近的函数。
and that’s a dramatic simplification. After all, a curve is a rather complicated object,
而这是一种戏剧性的简化。毕竟，曲线是一个相当复杂的对象。
and a straight line is perhaps the simplest of geometrical objects. If you can replace a function
而直线也许是最简单的几何对象。如果你能把一个函数
with its tangent line, that’s great, and that’s the topic of this lesson. Namely, we’d like to
与它的切线，很好，这就是本节课的主题。也就是说，我们要
talk about linear approximations, but we’ll also talk about so-called differentials
谈论线性近似，但我们也会谈论所谓的微分。
and some of their applications.
以及它们的一些应用。
Let’s begin with the topic of linear approximation. You may recall that the tangent line at any point,
我们先说说线性近似的话题。大家可能还记得，任何一点的切线。
x = a, is given by an equation of that type. Now, the y over here is a point on the tangent line,
x=a，由该类型的方程给出。现在，这里的y是切线上的一个点。
but what you could do is to replace y by f[x], the function itself, and then you get
但你可以用f[x]代替y，也就是函数本身，然后你可以得到
an approximate quality whereby the value of f at x can be approximated by using its derivative
近似质量，即f在x处的值可以用其导数来近似。
at the point a. This approximation is called the linear approximation of f at a
在点a处。这个近似称为f在a处的线性近似。
because the tangent line is being used to approximate f. Here’s a picture. You have the function
因为切线被用来逼近f。这里有一张图片。你的函数是
and you have tangent line, and the tangent line is now called the linearization.
而你有切线，现在的切线叫做线性化。
Linear approximations are a very important tool in calculus, and as an example,
线性近似是微积分中非常重要的工具，以此为例。
let’s take this function, f[x] = Sqrt[x + 8]. What we want to do is to approximate values of
让我们把这个函数，f[x]=Sqrt[x+8]。我们要做的是近似地求出以下的值
the square root at 8.98 and 9.03 within this function. Obviously when x is 1,
的平方根在8.98和9.03这个函数内。显然，当x为1时。
the square root of 9 is just 3, so what we do is we work near 1, and we get back f'[1] is 1/6.
9的平方根只是3，所以我们要做的是在1附近进行运算，得到的结果是f'[1]是1/6。
Now you set up the equation of the tangent line. Tangent is equal to 3 + (1/6)(x − 1),
现在你设置切线的方程。切线等于3+（1/6）（x-1）。
and you get back the tangent expression. Now when x is 0.98, you are at 8.98.
你就可以得到切线表达式。现在，当x为0.98时，你在8.98处。
The next one is 1.03—then you are at 9.03. You can use the tangent line to approximate
下一个是1.03-那么你就在9.03。你可以用切线来近似地计算出
the values over there, and those are the square roots at those two points approximately.
那边的值，这些是这两点的平方根大约。
Here’s the picture, and in the picture, you see you have the function, the linear approximation
这是图片，在图片中，你看到你有函数，线性近似。
and the values at the nearby points. You can see that the approximations are very, very close
以及附近各点的数值。你可以看到这些近似值非常非常接近于
to the original function, though of course they are not exactly the same.
到原来的功能，当然它们并不完全相同。
Okay. The question now is how accurate is that approximation? Suppose you want to have
好吧，现在的问题是，这个近似值有多准确？现在的问题是这个近似值有多准确？假设你想有
an accuracy of within 0.5 units. Well, here’s the equation. That’s the exact expression
精度在0. 5个单位以内好了，这里的公式。这就是准确的表达方式
and that’s the tangent. You want that difference to be less than 0.5. What you can do is
这就是切入点。你希望这个差值小于0. 5。你可以做的是
set up an equation with the reduced function and solve. Numerically, the values
用还原函数设方程并求解。从数字上看，数值为
lie between −6.3 and 14.39. As long as you stay within that range of x, you’ll get an approximation
位于-6.3和14.39之间。只要你保持在这个范围内x，你就会得到一个近似值，即
which is correct within 0.5 units. Now, let’s say you want to increase the accuracy to be less than 0.1.
的正确性在0.5个单位之内。现在，我们假设你想把精度提高到小于0.1。
Then you set up the equation with 1/10 over here, and you get back the values. In this case,
然后你在这边用1/10设置方程，就能得到回值。在这种情况下，
we have a much tighter range from −3.04 to 6.2, roughly.
我们有一个更紧密的范围，从-3.04到6.2，大概。
Okay. In physics, one needs this notion of linear approximation all the time.
好吧，在物理学中，人们一直需要这种线性近似的概念。
For example, when one studies the pendulum and you want to talk about
例如，当一个人研究摆的时候，你要谈的是什么？
the period of the pendulum, you start with the equation for the acceleration.
摆的周期，你从加速度的方程开始。
That’s the tangential acceleration at and g is the acceleration for gravity.
这就是切向加速度at，g是重力的加速度。
θ is the angle that the pendulum makes with the vertical. The point is that
θ是钟摆与垂直面所成的角度。关键是
when your rate goes to 0, then sine has got a slope of 1 because cosine of 0 is 1,
当你的速率为0，那么正弦的斜率为1，因为0的余弦为1。
and the value of sine at (0, 0)—so near 0 when θ is very small, Sin[θ] is approximately equal to θ.
和正弦在(0，0)的值--所以当θ非常小时，在0附近，Sin[θ]近似等于θ。
If you replace the Sin[θ] over there with the θ, then you get back a much simpler equation,
如果你把那边的Sin[θ]换成θ，那么你就会得到一个更简单的公式。
and that’s the one that’s used in physics textbooks at the elementary level. As you go more advanced,
而这是一个在物理教科书中使用的初级水平。随着你去更先进的。
of course you might want a better approximation. Here’s a picture of the actual acceleration,
当然，你可能想要一个更好的近似值。这里有一张实际加速度的图片。
the current one, and the linear approximation. Of course, you see that they are both
当前的，和线性近似。当然，你看它们都是
very close by as long as you do not go very far away from 0.
很近的地方，只要你不走很远，从0。
Okay. A related notion is the notion of a differential. To understand that, remember that
好吧，一个相关的概念是微分的概念。一个相关的概念是微分的概念。为了理解这个概念，请记住
the derivative is sometimes denoted as dy/dx. Now dy/dx is the same as f'[x],
的导数有时表示为dy/dx.现在&lt;i&gt;dy&lt;/i&gt;/&lt;i&gt;dx&lt;/i&gt;与&lt;i&gt;f&lt;相同。现在dy/dx与f'[x]相同。
so if you kind of cross-multiply, then you get the equation dy = f'[x]dx.
所以，如果你种交叉相乘，那么你会得到公式dy=f'[x]dx。
These quantities dx and dy are called differentials, so they represent the change in x
这些量dx和dy被称为微分，所以它们表示x的变化。
and the change in y respectively. Of course if you’re given dx over here, then you can
和y的变化分别。当然，如果在这里给你dx，那么你可以用
work out dy using f'[x]. That’s like a small machine where as you put in different dxs over here,
用f'[x]计算出dy。这就像一台小机器，你在这里输入不同的dx。
you get different dys over there. Here’s a picture. The picture is that
你得到不同的dys在那里。这里有一张图片。这张图是
as you stay close to x over here, then you can use the approximation to find the change in y.
由于你在这里接近x，那么你可以用近似值来计算y的变化。
But of course that’s still approximate, so the question is how does that relate to the actual differences?
但当然这还是近似的，那么问题是这和实际的差异有什么关系呢？
Here’s an example where you have a function, and the problem is to work out df,
这里有一个例子，你有一个函数，问题是要计算出df。
the approximate change, and the actual change when x goes from 3 to 3.05. Let’s first work out
的近似变化，以及x从3到3.05时的实际变化。我们先来计算一下
the exact change using subtraction. Now here is the approximate change given by df,
用减法求出确切的变化。现在这里是由df给出的近似变化。
and you can see they are pretty close to each other. In general, that’s the equation for
而且你可以看到它们是相当接近的。一般来说，这就是公式为
the change in f when you make a small change in x. Here’s a picture of the function
当您对x做一个小的改变时，f的变化。下面是函数的图片
and its approximation, and you can see, again, that as long as you stay close to 3,
和它的近似值，你可以看到，同样，只要你保持接近3。
the approximation is quite good.
的近似值相当不错。
Okay. The question is why are differentials important? The reason why they’re important is that
好吧，问题是为什么差价很重要？问题是为什么差价很重要？为什么它们很重要的原因是
sometimes you may not be able to find Δf that actually is f exactly, and then you might as well
有时你可能找不到实际就是f的Δf，那么你可能会发现
use the differential because they are really quite helpful and easy to work with.
使用差速器，因为他们真的很有帮助，很容易合作。
In fact, what we’re talking about over here is exactly the same as linear approximations.
其实，我们这边说的和线性近似完全一样。
Here’s the equation for a linear approximation in the differential language:
这是微分语言中线性近似的方程。
f[x + dx] is the value of f[x] + f'[x]dx. As an example, here is the function Sqrt[x + 8] again.
f[x+dx]是f[x]+f'[x]dx的值。举个例子，这里又是函数Sqrt[x+8]。
That’s the differential. You plug in the value of −0.02 for dx, and then you see that it’s pretty close
这就是差值。你插入dx的-0.02值，然后你会发现它非常接近
to the value of the function at 0.98. The point is that differentials are
到0.98时的函数值。关键是微分是
just another way of talking about linear approximations.
只是另一种方式谈论线性近似。
Okay. One important place where they are useful is when you want to estimate errors.
好吧，我知道了一个重要的地方，他们是有用的 当你想估计误差。
For example, suppose that the radius of the sphere is 11 cm and you know that
例如，假设小球的半径是11厘米，你知道
the error in measurement is about 0.1 cm. What you want to do is to find out
测量的误差约为0.1厘米。你要做的是找出
the maximum error when you calculate the volume of the sphere.
计算球体体积时的最大误差。
Now the volume of a sphere is 4/3πr^3, so you differentiate that equation. Now volume prime
现在一个球体的体积是4/3πr^3，所以你要对这个方程进行微分。现在体积质数
is the same as dvol/dr, so you can rewrite the equation as dvol = 4π^2dr,
与dvol/dr相同，所以可以将方程改写为dvol=4π^2dr。
and then because r is 11 and dr is 0.1—that’s the error—you can work out the error in the volume.
然后因为r是11，dr是0.1--这就是误差--你可以计算出体积的误差。
It turns out to be 152, approximately. Now that looks like a huge number.
原来是152人，大约。现在看起来是一个巨大的数字。
The question is why is it so large? Well, the point is that you really need to talk about
问题是为什么这么大？好吧，问题的关键是，你真的需要谈论的是
the relative error over here to understand what’s happening. The relative error is the error
相对误差在这边，才能明白发生了什么。相对误差是指
divided by the actual volume, and then that is just 0.027, so of course things look
除以实际的体积，然后就是0.027，所以事情当然会看起来
much better than they did before. If you do not plug in the value of r over here,
比以前好得多。如果你不把r的值插在这边。
then the relative error looks like 3dr/r, but that’s just 3 times the relative error and the radius.
那么相对误差看起来像3dr/r，但这只是相对误差和半径的3倍。
That says that the error in the volume is three times the error in the radius,
这说明体积的误差是半径误差的三倍。
provided that you talk about relative elements. Now the other way to talk about these errors
前提是你要谈论相对元素。现在，另一种谈论这些错误的方式是
is to use a percentage error. The percentage error in this case
是使用百分比误差。本例中的百分比误差
is 2.7 for the volume and 0.9 for the radius.
体积为2.7，半径为0.9。
Okay. That brings us to the end of this lesson, and the main point is that
好了，我们就到这里了。这就到了本课的最后，主要内容是
linear approximations are very important in mathematics and science. All we do
线性近似在数学和科学中是非常重要的。我们所做的
in such a case is replace a function by its tangent line. As long as you stay close to the point,
在这种情况下，就是用它的切线代替函数。只要你离点近就可以了。
then the approximation is very close to the actual function. One place where you might find them
那么这个近似值就非常接近实际函数。你可能会在一个地方找到它们
really useful is in physics, but of course they are also useful in chemistry
真正有用的是物理学，但当然它们在化学中也有用。
and in economics and in finance. Wherever you go, you will find the need to use linear approximations.
以及在经济学和金融学中。无论你走到哪里，你都会发现需要使用线性近似。
Another way of talking about these approximations is to use differentials,
谈论这些近似的另一种方式是使用微分。
and those are particularly useful when you want to talk about errors in measurements.
而当你想讨论测量中的误差时，这些特别有用。
That brings me to the end of this lesson. In the next lesson we’ll talk about maxima and minima,
这节课就到此结束了。下一节课我们要讲的是最大值和最小值。
but before doing that, we will have a problem session to go over some examples
但在这之前，我们会有一个问题环节，去了解一些例子。
for errors and approximations, and then we’ll get back to maxima and minima.
误差和近似值，然后我们再来讨论最大值和最小值。
I hope you’ve found this lesson useful. It’s a very important lesson.
我希望你觉得这堂课有用。这是一个非常重要的课程。
Do review it and be ready for the next session. Thank you.
做好复习，为下节课做好准备。谢谢你。